As though we are atop living stilts which continuously grow,
occasionally taller even than church belfries,
until eventually, walking becomes difficult and dangerous
and at last, the fall.
They're coming.
Three clicks left...
Four clicks right...
One click left...
Two clicks right...
Now!
You did it, Kougami!
I say, it is the cruel law of art that
human beings should die
and that we ourselves must die after
exhausting the gamut of suffering,
so that the grass, not of oblivion but of eternal life
may grow, the thick grass of fecund works.
Do an equipment check.
Power the glasses.
Download the map and our schedule.
No problems. They're working.
Don't deviate from the specified route.
Let's go.
Did you find something?
It's nice to see that my customers got here safely.
Identity confirmed.
You are Mr. Miyazaki?
Hey c'mon. Give me a sec.
Let me turn my translator on first.
Say something.
We need a car.
Okay. Let's get down to business.
I want it just as I ordered it earlier.
An older-model car, without interior cameras.
It needs to have the lifeform scanners fooled too.
Not a problem.
Show me the money, and I'll get you anything.
Don't get tagged by the street scanners, alright?
I can tell just by looking at you guys
that your Psycho-Passes aren't good.
I'm surprised you found this place.
I've been using an information broker these days.
Huh.
Sort of like one of those old-school detectives.
You see the info from the Pillbugs
on your Terminals, right?
They're probably illegal immigrants,
although I don't know how they got in.
Six foreigners,
and one probable black market broker.
A quick Hue Check shows that they're all past the limit.
Checking their Crime Coefficients with the Dominators
will probably say the same thing.
What's the plan of attack?
Once we block the entrance to the parking garage with drones,
we'll split into emergency staircase
and elevator teams.
We've verified that there are no traps
at either of our entry points.
So,
Ginoza and Kunizuka will take the stairs with me.
will take the stairs with me.
Inspector Shimozuki will take the elevator with
Sugou and Hinakawa,
putting two drones in the lead.
Roger that.
First, my team will enter
using flashbang grenades,
which will distract the enemy.
At that time, Inspector Shimotsuki's team
will enter from the rear and flank the enemy,
trapping all of them.
Flashbangs?
You're being really careful.
If the information from the Pillbugs is correct,
the enemy is equipped with firearms.
You mean...
If we allow the enemy to counterattack,
there will likely be casualties.
Take extreme caution.
Roger.
ฮืมมม
ถ้าอย่างงั้น การซื้อขายก็เป็นอันเสร็จ
หือ ?
ชิบหายละ พวกเจ้าหน้าที่
นี่คือหน่วยงานรักษาความสงบ
อย่าขัดขืนแล้วยอมจำนนซะ
(แปลตรงๆ มันจะได้ว่า อย่าทำอะไรเปล่าประโยชน์)
ค่าสัมประสิทธิ์อาชญากรรมเกิน 170.
เป็นเป้าหมายปราบปรามค่ะ
ทำการปลดล๊อกเซฟตี้แล้วค่ะ
ยิงสวนไป !
พวกนั้นเป็นใครกัน ?
ท่าทางคุ้นเคยกับการรบ
ค่าสัมประสิทธิ์อาชญากรรม 310.
Lethal Eliminator
เป้าหมายต้องกำจั . . .
ค่าสัมประสิทธิ์อาชญากรรม 326.
Lethal Eliminator
แม่งเอ๊ย !
เป็นเป้าหมายปราบปรามค่ะ
แก้ไขการประเมินภัยคุกคามของเป้าหมาย
รูปแบบระเบิด Destroy Decomposer
จับไว้!
รับทราบค่ะ
นี่คือหน่วยงานรักษาความสงบ
โปรดอย่าขัดขืน
วางอาวุธที่มีทั้งหมด
และกรุณามอบตัวด้วย
นี่คือ . . . .
หยุดแค่นั้นแหละ !
วางอาวุธลงแล้วหันหน้ามาทางนี้ซะ
ค่อยๆ หันมาช้าๆ
หยุดนะ!
ค่าสัมประสิทธิ์อาชญากรรม 293
เป้าหมายปราบปราม
นี่คือโลกที่สามารถวัดสภาพจิตใจและคาดการณ์บุคลิกภาพของมนุษย์ได้
สภาพจิตใจทุกรูปแบบจะถูกประเมินเป็นตัวเลข ที่สามารถใช้ตัดสินความผิดชอบชั่วดีของผู้คนเหล่านั้นได้ ซึ่งตัวเลขพวกนี้ถูกเรียกว่า "Psycho-Pass"
หากผู้ใดมีค่าสัมประสิทธิ์อาชญากรรมเกินเกณฑ์ที่กำหนด
คนคนนั้นจะถูกตราหน้าว่าเป็น "อาชญากรแฝง" ซึ่งจะถูกจับแยกไปบำบัด
กระทรวงสาธารณสุขและสวัสดิการมีหน้าที่ในการควบคุมเครือข่ายขนาดใหญ่
เพื่อคอยสอดส่องอาชญากรแฝง และดูแลสภาพจิตใจของประชากรภายในระบบ
ซึ่งระบบดังกล่าวเป็นที่รู้จักกันในนาม
ระบบซิบิล (Sybil System)
ไปประมือกับอาชญากรติดอาวุธ แต่ก็ไม่มีผู้เสียชีวิต
ทำได้ดีมาก
การสอบปากคำ
จะเริ่มเมื่ออาการจาก Paralyzer ของผู้ต้องหาหมดลงค่ะ
จนถึงตอนนั้นไปพักผ่อนให้สบายเถอะ
กลุ่มผู้ลักลอบเข้าประเทศ มีอาวุธปืน
มีแว่นเทคโนโลยีขั้นสูง
ที่ถูกพัฒนาโดยใครบางคน
ซึ่งมีความรู้เรื่องระบบรักษาความปลอดภัยของประเทศนี้
ต้องการจะบอกอะไร ?
อะไรบางอย่าง
ที่แปลกๆ กำลังเกิดขึ้นอยู่ไม่ใช่เหรอ ?
แน่นอน
มีหลายๆ เรื่องกำลังเกิดขึ้น
จะแปลกรึเปล่านั้น ก็ไม่ใช่หน้าที่ของเธอที่ต้องใส่ใจ
ยังไงก็ตาม
ขอไว้หลังจากการสอบปากคำก็แล้วกัน
ค่ะ ?
ผู้สังเกตการณ์ชิโมสึกิ
มาหาชั้นที่ออฟฟิศหน่อย
แต่งงานเหรอ ?
อืม
เพราะว่าฝ่ายนั้นก็ยุ่งๆ เหมือนกัน
งานแต่งเลยดูเหมือนจะต้องเลื่อนไปอีกหน่อย
แต่ยังไงก็อยากแนะนำให้อาคาเนะรู้จักอยู่ดีน่ะ
ในที่สุดคาโอริก็แต่งงานกับเค้าเหรอเนี่ย
ยินดีด้วยนะ
ขอบใจจ๊ะ
ระบบซิบิลหาแฟนให้ใหม่อีกครั้งเนี่ย
สุดยอดจนไม่อยากจะเชื่อเลยนะเนี่ย
ต้องขอบคุณระบบนี้ ที่ทำให้ได้เจอกับเค้าน่ะนะ
พอตัดสินใจแล้วก็เลยบอกครอบครัวทั้งสองฝ่ายไปน่ะ
ถึงอย่างงั้น ตอนแรก
ก็ไม่ใช่ว่าจะไม่มีปัญหาซะทีเดียวหรอก
แต่สุดท้าย
เค้าก็เป็นผู้ชายที่เหมาะกับชั้นจริงๆ
นะ ถึงแม้ว่าจะมีเรื่องอะไรเล็กๆ น้อยๆ ก็เถอะนะ
งั้นเหรอ
ความสงบสุขในตอนนี้ . . . .
เพราะหน่วยงานรักษาความสงบที่อาคาเนะทำงานอยู่ใช่มั้ยล่ะ ?
อือ
If Sybil
can find us the path to happiness
better than we ever could,
maybe someday,
Sybil will be able to save everyone on Earth.
I wonder about that...
And now news regarding
the Sybil Export Program,
currently being conducted to aid SEAUn.
The experimentally deployed Sybil System
in the capital of Shamballa Float
which had issues with its initial roll-out,
is now functioning well...
It's impressive
that we could bring peace and order to a
war-torn nation.
I wonder...
where he is and what he's doing?
What's going on,
Shion?
I'm using a secure line right now.
Don't tell anybody that we had this conversation.
Inspector Shimotsuki is operating under the Chief's orders.
What's she doing?
I can't defy a superior's orders.
Get here as fast as you can.
I don't know what she's trying to do,
but could you stop her?
Can you buy some time?
Sorry, it's too late for that.
I'm so sorry.
You performed a Memory Scoop for the investigation?
What the hell were you thinking?
Don't get mad at me...
Chief's orders.
It's not Analyst Karanomori's fault.
The man was a confirmed Latent Criminal.
Just because there's no precedent
doesn't mean it's illegal.
That's awful.
We gave him some drugs
to make his brainwaves stand out more.
We've never had armed illegal immigrants come in before,
and on top of that, he's a Latent Criminal.
It's not like he has any rights we need to consider.
Thanks to that, I got results.
Results?
The Chief wants to see you.
What the hell are you using Inspector Shimotsuki for?
Investigating the incident.
You have no shame!
It's an incident all the same.
We did what had to be done.
Look at this.
I'm certain that you'll recognize him.
He was under your command, after all.
A group of foreign terrorists smuggle themselves in,
and their memories contain an Enforcer who deserted three years ago.
Very interesting, don't you think?
You see, my theory is that
Kougami Shinya has finally become a true criminal.
We've even determined where the illegal immigrants came from.
It was SEAUn.
They originated there,
and were terrorists involved in anti-government operations.
The Southeast Asian Union,
they're the ones in charge of managing the Sybil System?
That's right.
The current capital, the artificial island of Shamballa Float
is being administered as a Special Ward, and is also a
test case for remote management of the Sybil System.
However, the region is currently gripped by internal strife.
The top-grade armed drones we currently have in place
have been destroyed far more frequently as of late.
That also resembles him quite well.
There have occasionally been tales of hunters,
who in their zeal to catch their prey
end up becoming the prey themselves.
I don't know how he escaped, or what route he took,
but let's say that Kougami Shinya is hiding overseas,
and he's sending criminals over to Japan.
If he wanted to jeopardize the Sybil System,
that's a halfway decent plan.
Kougami wouldn't do that.
Then what do you think of the results of this memory montage?
Kougami Shinya and this terror group
might be connected in some way.
But,
we can't say with certainty that it proves he's become a criminal.
We should bring out the truth by investigating this.
We've identified the country that you came from.
Why did you come to Japan from SEAUn?
It must have something to do with the exportation of the Sybil System.
Right?
What can you tell me about this man?
Even if you don't talk, someone will.
No one will tell you anything.
What?
You animals lost sight of true justice
when you entrusted your fate to an oracle machine.
Our wars won't make any sense to you now.
You're asking about the possibility that
Kougami Shinya aided and abetted a crime?
That's right.
Maybe he isn't on the battlefield personally,
but his plan is to organize and lead people
to carry out his crimes.
Do you think that he's capable of that?
Like Makishima Shougo, for example?
Yes.
I'd like to say that it isn't possible,
but I also can't deny that the answer is colored by my personal feelings.
What Kougami is doing now wasn't captured by any of my predictions.
But...
If you want to live life
according to your professional duties,
you need to mold your soul
into the part assigned to you by society.
Kougami walked that path once.
But,
as he worked to capture Makishima, one who deviated from the mold,
he ended up deviating from what was expected of him as well.
Oh... You're applying to conduct your investigation abroad?
Yes.
You want to go to SEAUn personally?
The special ward of Shamballa Float is operated by the Sybil System.
In other words, the Japanese Ministry of Health and Welfare
is entrusted with police powers.
Naturally, as it is enforced by one of its departments, the Bureau of Public Safety,
your actions will be permitted.
However,
you will be stepping into a lawless land the minute you set foot
outside Shamballa Float,
and this is why they will attempt to keep you within the Ward,
and they will not provide any aid in
the search for Kougami Shinya.
Is that all right with you?
I'm more than prepared.
There's an air mail transport leaving tomorrow.
It's a jet plane used to deliver sensitive equipment.
How many will be accompanying you?
Just me is enough.
If we consider what you know about us,
it's probably best that you're going alone.
I offered to come along, but they turned me down.
I'm not surprised.
Inspectors are never deployed abroad, after all,
let alone Enforcers.
I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
If you manage to meet up with him,
give him a punch for me.
I can't do that.
What?
If I find him, I'll arrest him and bring him back,
so I want you to punch him yourself.
I can't tell whether you've changed or not.
You're a mystery as always.
Good to have you along, Miss Ministry of Health and Welfare.
I'm glad to be here.
It's been a long time since we've brought along a living person.
All order and morality simply vanished into the chaos.
Nowadays, the vast majority of humanity is now forced to live lives no better than animals,
driven only by the compulsions of their desires.
Will they live in the cage that is the Sybil System?
Or will they step outside, and submit themselves to the Law of the Jungle?
Either way,
there's no longer any place on Earth that respects the ideologies and dignity of their fellow humans.
You've got to respect the strength it takes
to muster the willpower
and do what's necessary to live life according to your values
while forging your own destiny.
Especially to those who have been put in such a bind by their predicaments
that they're willing to go out and commit crimes.
Makishima Shougo demonstrated that strength,
and in the process of trying to catch him,
Kougami demonstrated it as well.
Yes.
Hey, does the SEAUn government
know who you really are?
Of course not.
Do you really think we would reveal a national secret to people overseas?
As of today, we've given SEAUn
street scanners for Cymatic Scanning
and the ability to send the collected data back to Japan.
We have forbidden their use of Dominators
and we have left the matter of public order
to the nation's military police.
To them, the Sybil System
is a black box somewhere overseas.
I'm surprised Chairman Han was willing to
accept an enigmatic system like that.
It simply goes to show how important it was to restore public order quickly.
It was a good opportunity.
I think it would be valuable for you to see just how scarce and valuable
something like peace is in the outside world.
Perhaps you will once again
become aware of Sybil's greatness.
This craft will arrive at SEAUn International Airport in fifteen minutes.
We will now be preparing to land,
so please fasten your seat belt.
I am Nicholas Wong, the captain of the Union Military Police.
You must be Inspector Akane Tsunemori, from the Japanese Ministry of Health and Welfare?
Yes.
Welcome.
We welcome you and the Sybil System.
Are you shocked at how bad the situation is down here?
No...
Every country around the world is like this right now.
Except Japan, that is.
Is it really that dangerous around here?
This is one of the better parts of town.
The Junta in charge has been crushed.
This civil war is coming to a close.
So by that, you mean
that the war isn't quite over?
That's right.
At present, disruptive elements of the population opposed to the current regime remain.
Ahead of us lies Shamballa Special Ward,
where the Sybil System is being experimentally started.
Only those whose Hue and Crime Coefficient are at normal levels are permitted
permitted to enter.
〈Please, let me into Shamballa Float!〉
It's thanks to your country.
〈Please, open up!〉
Hurry up and remove her.
〈Let me in, please!〉
〈Don't move! Move and I'll shoot!〉
Don't worry about it.
This happens quite often.
This bus is only for residents authorized by the Sybil System.
Who are those people with the collars?
You've noticed them, have you?
They are Latent Criminals.
That device allows allows them to move about freely,
but constantly monitors their Psycho-Pass.
If their hue clouds, their Crime Coefficient is immediately measured.
Depending on their Coefficient,
the device can inject a sedative or a lethal poison.
While allowing them to live among the general population
is harmful to the Area Stress levels,
we still haven't been able to
isolate our nation quite as well as Japan has,
thus this arrangement is only temporary.
Soldiers wear them too?
Yes... you might call them "Enforcers."
The entire officer corps has clean Hues,
so we can act as "Inspectors."
By the way, Inspector Tsunemori,
Yes?
If you plan to step outside Shamballa Float,
or enter important facilities, you must go with an escort of our choosing,
and coordinate your visits with us.
You need someone to come with me?
Will that be inconvenient?
No.
I'm an Inspector from the Japanese Ministry of Health and Welfare's Bureau of Public Safety,
Inspector Tsunemori Akane.
I am Chuan Han.
I didn't think you'd come to greet me personally,
Chairman.
It simply means that we are very interested
in both you and your country.
You must be tired from your long journey. Please, sit.
Okay.
We would like your assistance in an international investigation...
The man you are pursuing,
is apparently a terrorist aiding the guerillas?
Yes, we suspect him of that.
This nation's efforts to take countermeasures against the guerillas are a stubborn effort at suppression;
we would not refer to it as an "investigation."
We will provide you with plenty of support, of course.
However, remember that the situation in this country
is fundamentally different from that of your own.
I only ask that you keep that in mind.
Understood.
Very well. Colonel?
I leave her in your care. Treat her well.
Leave it to me.
Open case.
Hm?
Sign: Open this if you're in a bind.
...Geez, come on, Shion.
Chuan Han, former Army general.
In the internal disunity that plagued the Union
12 years ago,
he was one of the generals competing for hegemony.
By making an agreement
to create a Sybil-controlled Special Ward within SEAUn,
he gained the backing of the Japanese government, and gained supremacy over his rivals.
It's been two years since he re-established the parliament and named himself Chairman.
But the voices of rebellion still cry out against the military government.
The situation within the country is still unstable.
The terrorists that came to Japan
were probably anti-government guerillas.
The foundation of Han's power base is the support of the Japanese government,
and as a result, Tokyo became the target of terrorists seeking revenge.
I will be taking care of your surroundings.
I am called Yeo. If you need anything,
please do not hesitate to ask.
If you would like something to eat, it would be no trouble
for me to prepare something for you right now.
If you plan to go out again,
I have been informed that as long as you do not
venture into secure areas or cross the bridge,
you may go wherever you wish.
I understand.
In one week's time, Sybil will
put restrictions on the alcohol trade,
so if you would like to sample some, now is your chance.
Um...
Yes?
Can you answer a personal question?
I will answer it if I'm able to.
Do you...
consider your life on Shamballa to be a happy one?
Of course.
Everyone who lives in this Special Ward
is thankful that Chairman Han
introduced the Sybil System.
After all,
there was no such thing as a safe place in this country until very recently.
This is not my fault! He did it!
How 'bout it?
All green.
Move out.
What?
Mind if I join you?
I don't mind, but don't do anything rash
when the fighting starts.
Of course. I understand.
What kind of operation is this?
The ruined old capital
is 50 kilometers north of here.
It's a ghost town now,
but yesterday, we learned that there is a high probability
that the anti-government guerillas have a base here.
I was under the impression that our drones
were being lent to you for peacekeeping purposes, am I right?
Do you intend to use them for something other than policing the Ward?
Taking care of latent threats is just another one of our duties.
It's nothing that goes against the agreement.
Shamballa Float is just the first step in
getting the Sybil System a foothold here.
We'll eventually have to expand its control
across the entire nation.
In order to do that, we must crush all armed opposition
and measure the Psycho-Passes of everyone in the country.
Commence attack!
Roger!
All units, switch to combat mode.
We are commencing our attack.
〈Get to the point, hurry!〉
This is horrible.
If the Cymatic Scan doesn't have a problem with it,
the safety gets unlocked.
Their Crime Coefficients
must be at least that of Latent Criminals.
There's no way that anybody's Psycho-Pass would
give good numbers in a situation like this!
It's kill or be killed.
And unfortunately, we have no form
of mental care to help rehabilitate these people.
In the new SEAUn,
only the citizens who are needed will remain.
These guys are,
to put it bluntly,
the leftovers of our civil war days.
Activating Skandas.
Commencing mobilization.
Lost communication with Ganga 02.
I think it was shot down.
We've also lost Ganga 03!
And also Ganga 01! It was shot down!
It's that guy.
Start the counterattack. Do exactly as I told you.
〈Go! Let's move!〉
We're losing control of the Ganeshas and Skandas
deployed at all points.
It doesn't matter. The drones will restart soon
and go into stand-alone mode.
They can't measure Psycho-Passes,
but it's fine as long as the Identify Friend-Foe system works.
Don't you think that restart time is what they're after?
All units have restarted.
Good. Commence counterattack.
Leave our escort units here, and commit the reserves.
What the hell are you doing?
Investigating the incident.
You need to stay with me!
I'll keep the enemy occupied here.
We're in control now!
But if you don't keep your eyes open, this could turn into a massacre!
It's been a while,
Kougami.
I can't say that I expected you to chase me all the way out here.
You're under arrest.
Arrest? Do you realize the situation we're in?
Are you the one who sent
terrorists to Japan?
What? What are you talking about?
Then...
Well, Inspector? Are you gonna stop me,
or let me go?
Jump in!
Kougami.
I'll cooperate with you.
Hey now.
It's only temporary.
Just for the investigation.
Got it, Inspector.
Colonel!
Remove her from the Identify Friend-Foe system!
But...
This is a battlefield. The mission has priority.
It'll take time. We have to send the system back to headquarters first.
No abdominal hernias.
No pelvic abnormalities.
The pubis is joined properly.
No lumbar vertebrae abnormalities.
No femoral abnormalities.
No abnormalities in the limbs.
Get me a neck brace.
Hurry up. We're moving out soon.
What's going on here?
Explain.
It's exactly what it looks like.
I'm taking part in the democratization of the country.
Where are you going next?
I'm going back to base camp.
By the way, Inspector.
Quit calling me that.
Have you met Chairman Han?
Oh, yeah. I met him yesterday.
Don't you think there's something off about him?
Huh?
I wonder what a dictator's
Crime Coefficient looks like?
So, the mission was a failure,
and our Japanese Inspector, Tsunemori, is missing?
Her conduct was tantamount to aiding the guerillas.
She acted completely without authorization!
Be that as it may,
she was a foreign guest in your custody.
This is a question of responsibility.
But!
I'm joking.
The Japanese government understands
the state this country is in.
You wouldn't expect them to send her here alone in that knowledge if her life mattered to them.
This situation is most regrettable.
If anything, Colonel, you should prepare yourself for even bigger trouble.
What?
It's entirely possible that she was sent here precisely
because they know that she's capable of surviving in these conditions.
I'm very interested in seeing how this plays out.
I have an urgent job for you.
Of course, there will be a reward.
I'm very grateful. We have more time than we know what to do with.
Near Siem Reap, there's a guerilla stronghold containing two Japanese.
One is a member of the group, the other, an Inspector from Tokyo who came to arrest him.
I want them taken care of.
The guerilla's one thing, but the Inspector too?
She's an agent of the Japanese government, right?
She looks as though she may get in the way. She's a hazard.
Here we go.
Since we got on board with Sybil,
how will we get our message out like this?
Thanks to Sybil, we have this paradise we call Shamballa.
You could live civilized lives here, if you wanted.
Just how long do you plan on playing savages
on your little island?
"At the level of the individual,
violence has a detoxifying effect.
It takes away the inferiority complexes,
and changes the contemplative and desperate attitude of native people.
Violence makes them fearless,
and restores their dignity in their own eyes."
You're not familiar with Frantz Fanon?
We're investigating the present whereabouts of the targets.
As soon as we find them...
Don't worry about it.
We mercenaries have our own intelligence network.
Most information can be bought with money or valuables.
Of course, I have to bill you for
the necessary expenses separately.
No problem.
I need military aircraft ground clearance
and IFF recognition codes.
Both the young and old are here, huh?
You're back, Kougami.
Who's she?
It's hard to explain,
but she isn't an enemy. She's a guest of mine, Sem.
Did Kougami show you the way too?
Then we're comrades.
I'm Sem. I act as the leader here.
I'm Tsunemori Akane. Nice to meet you.
I lost a lot of good men again. I'm sorry.
No.
If it weren't for you, we'd all be dead.
Is Gino doing well?
He became an Enforcer after that.
I see.
And what exactly are you doing in a place like this?
At first, I was looking for someplace quiet.
I was tired, you see.
But once I left the Sybil System,
I found that there weren't any quiet places left.
Everywhere around the world was a battlefield.
I thought I had prepared myself for that reality,
but I soon found out how naive I was.
I beat those survival instincts
into my body.
But why did you join the guerillas?
Soon after I came to this country,
Han's decrees
and the deployment of drones to hunt guerillas began.
So I decided to teach the guerillas
how to fight drones.
The drones are all made in Japan.
I know their weak points as well as
the best ways to defeat them.
But what do you hope to achieve by doing all this?
We may look like this now,
but at the time, it looked like we could win by toughing it out.
He might call himself "Chairman" now,
but Han is just a leader of one faction of the military.
He joined forces with Sybil
to get a leg up on his rivals.
His aim wasn't
to turn Shamballa Float into a paradise.
In all practicality, Han's real power
is the result of his faction being the strongest militarily.
We thought that would be his downfall.
The Sybil System is the basically the ultimate bureaucracy
and would be anathema to a dictator.
Once it got to the point where it could rule,
it would force everything into the system,
and leave the dictator powerless.
It was only a matter of time until Han figured out how terrifying Sybil could be
and we thought that once he realized that,
Shamballa Float would throw them out before they could finish construction.
That's what we thought a year ago, at least.
But... that isn't what happened.
Yeah.
Han opened up Shamballa to the experiment without a fight,
a floating paradise similar to Japan opened its gates,
and armed drones are still slaughtering
anti-government forces.
There has to be some angle we're not seeing
in the relationship between Han and Sybil.
But we can't give up
until we figure out what that is.
Is that what you call justice?
Ignore the law, involve anybody you can,
and continue to fight in order to satisfy your self-centered pride?
You sure learned how to talk back.
And you haven't changed at all.
Yeah... That's a relief.
So... you really didn't have anything to do with
the terrorists sent to Japan?
I do remember some who were saying that we should
take revenge on Japan, because it was where Sybil was based.
Sem and I were opposed to it
and they ended up leaving our camp
but they didn't seem like the types who would be able to cross the ocean on their own.
There's no mistaking them.
Samlin, Ma, Shim; it's those guys.
They had advanced hacking tools,
as well as the connections necessary to get in touch with a fence at the Waste Block.
Doesn't something seem off?
You're right.
I can only imagine that someone was guiding them.
Kougami.
Looks like both of us
have bitten off way more than we can chew.
Stay here tonight.
Tomorrow morning,
we'll get you to within walking distance of Shamballa Float.
If you stay quiet, you shouldn't be in any danger.
Would it be too much to ask you to turn yourself in?
Please,
don't tell Sem or the others that you're a detective.
If they find out you're involved with the government,
even they won't be able to ignore that.
Hey, it's already past time.
All clear.
Get moving.
Roger that.
The terrorists who came to Japan
had some rare paper books with them.
Proust's In Search of Lost Time.
I'll bet that was mine.
When Samlin was still here,
he kept bugging me about wanting to read it.
I thought I'd lost it, but I guess he took it.
The man named Sem,
he told me that you "showed him the way."
Are you sure you're not their spiritual leader
and not just a tactical advisor?
To be honest, it doesn't sit right with me, and it doesn't suit me.
But, it seems like the guys here
have been influenced too much by my words and behavior.
Even if you're not intending for it to happen,
you've got the ability to draw people to you;
it's almost like gravity.
It's just like Makishima Shougo.
Do we look similar to you?
You could accurately predict his next moves better than anyone else.
It wouldn't be unusual if you also possessed similar
talents and character traits.
At the very least, my words never
steered anyone wrong while I was still back in Japan.
So why now?
It's because you've changed the way you live your life.
Even if you can't see it,
the place you stand right now
is no different from where Makishima Shougo stood before.
Are you trying to say I'll become him?
No.
But I'd be willing to bet that people who want what you
and Makishima Shougo do will keep appearing.
The people who are angry and frustrated at society
are looking to pin their hopes on something...
I'm afraid they might try to
put you on a pedestal like they did to Makishima.
Sounds like a pain in the ass.
But you aren't the kind of guy who wants to control people's hearts.
That's the biggest difference between
you and Makishima Shougo.
If that's really what you thought of him,
then it's no wonder he's giving me so much trouble.
<Enemy attack! There are flames rising in the direction of Bayon!〉
Acquiring.
Weber, Babangida, keep sniffing around for them.
Copy that!
Break out the ECM!
Yuria, did you find the target?
Not yet.
Shit, only small fry here.
Hey, Boone!
That's fine. Search for the targets.
Roger.
These tactics are different from the military's.
How so?
They're not relying on drones;
They're highly trained special forces.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
Sem, where's my ECM?
They've seized the controls!
We're trying to stall them!
Sem!
We'll have her escape.
Kougami!
You need to leave without me.
We'll hold them off.
I'm not leaving alone!
Your criminal investigation
might get to the bottom of Han's crimes!
It's an opportunity for us.
Go back to Shamballa, and continue your mission!
But!
Don't worry.
Do you really think I'll die that easily?
If we both survive this,
come try to catch me again.
Sure.
Sem!
Go, Kougami!
Sem, get outta there!
I can't abandon a friend!
Sem!
Target Delta identified! Open fire!
Wait.
What about Target Juliet?
Signal lost. She's getting away.
Do you want me to chase her?
No, it's too late.
Get me Delta alive instead. Don't kill him.
I'll be right there.
Roger.
You're quite something.
You'll regret it if you don't kill me now.
Terrifying! Unfortunately, we have some important questions to ask you.
You may be an important guest of ours,
but there is a limit to our patience.
An "important guest?"
You tried to kill me!
It's because you were operating alongside the guerillas.
That was part of the investigation.
Why can't you understand that this is our country?
You will be jailed
and sent home immediately on the next flight to Japan.
Colonel, I'd rather you not decide important matters
without me.
Mister Chairman!
There is no need to deport her.
Simply put her under observation and return her to
her quarters.
But!
Silence!
It is not as if
I do not have issues with some of the Military Police's conduct as of late.
Also, I am the Commander-in-Chief.
Yes sir.
Well then...
Excuse me, Miss Tsunemori.
I see you have returned to your room,
so I have come to prepare your meal.
Thank you, Yeo.
I'll take my meal after my shower.
Yes, certainly.
Hm? Akane?
Sorry about this, Shion.
Can you hear me?
Yes, of course.
Looks like the program I gave you is working properly.
So, what is it?
Is it possible to systematically
inspect the Psycho-Pass diagnosis
equipment that the Public Saftey Bureau
gave Shamballa Float?
Sure.
It should be just fine if we use the Pillbugs, I think.
What do you hope to find?
The Sybil System is
in use over there, right?
In that case...
There's a possibility
that the system is not being used fairly.
Check the Ward's equipment,
and make sure you take a close look at the Military Police.
I need you to figure out ASAP if Cymatic Scans
are being measured accurately.
A detective's gut feeling... I take it?
It's not that.
It's just a conclusion I've drawn after looking at the facts.
All right. I'll inspect the hell out of this.
Oh, and one more thing.
The collars being used to manage Latent Criminals on Shamballa Float
are made in Japan, right?
Do you think you could get me a code to unlock them
under the Public Safety Bureau's authority?
Sounds simple enough, but will you be all right?
I don't think the Military Police will appreciate that.
I'm way past the phase where I make my decisions
just so I can please people.
Your meal is now ready.
Thank you.
Don't say a word.
Th-this is...
Calm down and listen to what I have to say.
I need your coopera...
tion...
This is...
I did just as you said!
You'll really remove my brother's collar now, won't you?
I'll have a good think about it.
Don't kill the girl yet.
I'll arrange for her to die with our guerilla military adversaries.
This should avoid any unnecessary suspicion.
I knew you guys
weren't undergoing
Cymatic Scans.
Oh?
Do you have proof?
You just killed someone, for god's sake!
As long as the Sybil System doesn't bitch about it,
it's not a crime.
Am I right?
Hey, did you buy them all?
These aren't regular army methods. Are you mercenaries?
You surprised me.
The guerilla military advisor, whom we've heard so much about, is a Japanese.
I was under the impression that the whole country had been turned into
spineless, phony wimps by the Sybil System.
Well, it's true that I don't have a place there anymore.
Did you decide to quit government work after getting professional training?
But you're still only a third rate mercenary.
After all, you still haven't grasped how to choose the right employer.
Don't lump me in with you hyenas.
I don't live my life sniffing for
blood in the water.
Oh, really now?
If you really were a detective, that's bullshit.
There are some who chant slogans,
saying that violence is both the law and just.
When society begins to collapse, violence becomes increasingly privatized.
That's because the state has monopolized
organized violence.
When violence begins to spread, it leaves the realm of politics.
The organized violence becomes an economic activity, with societal unrest at its heart.
The Wretched of the Earth, huh?
A mercenary obsessed with Post-Colonialism is something
I'd rather not deal with...
Oh, you have brains as well as brawn, do you?
This is getting even more interesting.
From what I've heard, it sounds as though
those guerillas really took a shine to you.
Did you whisper sweet nothings into their ears?
No idea.
But still, I've gotta wonder.
As I talk to you, I'm strangely getting into a better mood.
It's like I'm listening to Wagner or something.
Those are words
I'd rather hear from a glamorous woman instead.
Hearing it from a guy just makes my skin crawl.
You should be thankful for
the advice of your elders!
But that ability of yours is very precious, Mister Japanese.
You'd make a very good agitator.
You can incite rage and focus resentment;
that's a special kind of charisma.
Although it's modest,
we've been
managing our own little community.
We need to build our forces first, but we want to form our own faction.
And when that happens, we'll need
not only leadership,
but the ability to fire up the crowds and captivate them.
How 'bout it? Do you feel like joining us?
If we hone your abilities,
I can get you a squadron that you can use
to your heart's content.
Hey, boss!
If I go ahead and give you up to my client, you're dead anyway.
I'm saying that
I'm giving you a chance to live.
Don't expect me to thank you for offering me an option
I'd rather die than accept.
Hey, someone. Give him treatment.
Is he still alive? The male target.
Yeah. Can I kill him yet?
He still has some use.
Bring him to me.
Understood.
I would've liked to give you some time to change your mind,
but unfortunately, you're out of luck.
Kougami...
"The Japanese terrorist who joined the guerillas
managed to break free while being escorted,
took Inspector Tsunemori hostage and seized a helicopter.
He attempted to commit terrorist acts against the State,
and in our attempt to thwart him, we reluctantly shot the helicopter down."
That's how it'll go.
It sure is a waste to destroy one helicopter to kill two people.
This was all the result of a Public Safety Bureau Inspector's mistake.
We can petition Japan to reimburse us for damages.
I want to get rid of them quickly.
It's fine as long as we find some of their
remains in the wreckage.
Kill both of them. Now.
Do you really think you can keep hiding all of this?
How are you going to explain this to Chairman Han?
The Chairman?
The Japanese Government won't stay quiet about this either.
They're sure to do a detailed investigation.
What a pitiful stooge.
She knew not what her master's right hand was doing
while allowing the left hand to work her to the bone.
Hey, Miss, what would you say if I said that
we're actually operating according to the Japanese government's plan?
What?
Isn't that right, Colonel?
We took out Chairman Han at your request,
and apparently the Japanese government provided the body double who replaced him.
Hey!
Don't let another word slip!
Shoot them, now!
Hey, Nicholas...
What the hell is it doing?
This is the Public Safety Bureau Investigative Division.
According to paragraph three of the Sybil System Treaty,
and the powers vested in us by paragraph five,
the Japanese government will now be restoring public order.
Persons who exceed the Crime Coefficient threshold may be
eliminated without warning in some cases.
Please purge all thoughts of resistance, calm down,
and return your mental state to stability.
We repeat,
this is the Public Safety Bureau Investigative Division.
According to paragraph three of the Sybil System Treaty...
The Japanese Public Safety Bureau?
These outsiders
don't know anything!
Crime Coefficient is over 380.
Enforcement Mode: Lethal Eliminator.
Boss!
Kougami.
Tsunemori, you find the Chairman.
Okay.
Descending!
Are you all right, Inspector?
Why are you guys here...?
Karanomori was able to determine from
the Pillbug's data...
...that the Street Scanners here have all been illegally modified.
This place is a nest of Latent Criminals.
How did they do it?
They managed to insert the data from their IFF system
into their Hue scans.
Anybody judged as friendly by the IFF wouldn't be targeted by the scanners.
Nearly everyone in the Military Police
was able to fake their Psycho-Pass using this method.
They were able to fool the Sybil System
using such a brazen trick?
Sybil wasn't fooled, obviously.
They were merely being tolerated.
Exposing the Military Police all at once was Sybil's goal all along.
If you'd guessed that in the first place,
you wouldn't have had to go through all this trouble.
You sure love doing things the
roundabout way don't you, Senpai?
What do you mean?
You don't even need a Cymatic Scan
to figure out what these guys were thinking.
Even so,
we had no choice but to use them until SEAUn
had enough infrastructure to support Sybil.
Once Shamballa Float was complete,
they would have fulfilled their usefulness.
Then we'd just need to find evidence of their wrongdoing and dispose of them.
The whole part about pursuing an escaped Enforcer
was just an excuse to send you away.
And you're totally okay with all of this?
It takes those who are capable to do what needs to be done.
Basically, get your head out of your ass, Senpai.
In that case, let's do what needs to be done.
Dominator Portable Psychological Diagnosis and Suppression System
has been activated.
User authentication: Inspector Tsunemori Akane.
You are a valid user.
Inspector Shimotsuki,
you'll take Kunizuka, Hinakawa, and Sugou,
and take command of the site.
Okay.
I'm going to arrest the Chairman.
You're coming with me, Ginoza.
Roger.
This isn't time to be playing around.
You'll be in danger if you don't get out of here soon.
Or maybe you can't work up the motivation
unless you're chasing your prey?
Oh my.
You truly are a bloodhound, down to your very bones,
aren't you?
Do you really think I can let a guy who wants to form his own military force
get away scot-free?
What good does it do to believe that bullshit?
Besides, even if you hadn't gotten involved,
he would've ended up destroying himself anyway.
What is it that drives you?
Your sense of justice?
That's not it...
There are thousands of men like him.
Killing a guy like him wouldn't change a damn thing.
Even so, you continue to risk your life by hounding him.
Why are you so tenacious?
The dead need to stay silent!
I'm going it alone from here.
What's going on?
I want you to chase down Kougami.
Meaning,
I can deal with him however I'd like?
I'll leave it to you.
You aren't a detective, are you?
I'm a former detective.
That's not what I meant.
I meant you were born to be something different.
Crime Coefficient is zero.
He is not an enforcement target. The trigger will be locked.
Criminally Asymptomatic... I knew it.
You figured it out?
Someone revealed to me that you were a body double.
But I doubt he knew
that Japan's Ministries are already full of body doubles.
Yes...
Colonel Nicholas thought
that I was merely a person who had
undergone plastic surgery.
As it turns out, the current me
has only known him for about two days.
You see, I came to SEAUn on the same flight you did.
Switching bodies is a pain when you have to cross the ocean.
So it's just as Inspector Shimotsuki guessed.
It's all gone according to your plan, hasn't it,
Sybil System?
Colonel Nicholas' aim was to complete
the construction of Shamballa Float, even
if he had to overcome Han's opposition to it.
Japan offered up its unmanned weapons systems in exchange,
which ended up becoming our trump card in taking control of SEAUn.
We were attracted to the concept of setting up a model city
overseas that made use of the Sybil System.
What both parties needed was a
cooperative Chairman who would support
and greenlight the project.
Staging a foreign intervention...
conspiring to assassinate the real Chairman Han...
those are clearly criminal acts!
This nation, for all intents and purposes,
had no organized government.
Corruption. Discrimination. Racial strife that was almost religious in nature.
Two years ago, SEAUn was
a group of "allied nations" in name only.
All you wanted to do was expand the Sybil System's area of control.
We do not possess the simple
lust to expand our dominion that you believe we do.
"The greatest happiness of the greatest number."
In other words, it depends on how you define the extents.
You have judged our actions to be criminal behavior.
However, a crime is merely a deviation from the law.
Laws don't simply exist for their own sake.
The law wouldn't exist without the support of the people.
You've seized this country,
but you haven't received the consent of the people.
All you've done is fool a dictator and lie your way in.
In order to bring peace and quiet to a people
constantly at risk of starvation or slaughter,
it was necessary to take the fastest measures possible.
We deemed this to be the fastest and most optimal way of doing things.
You need to resign, Chairman Han.
And in a free election, select a new leader.
You need to discuss the pros and cons of bringing in the Sybil System,
and decide based on the consensus of the people.
And if the people of this nation reject us?
If, of their own will, the people opt to throw away this brief peace
and this shining city of dreams?
What's worth protecting
is something that can only be decided of your own volition.
Don't just force them to obey,
but make them want to
take the law and continue to protect it.
I reluctantly understand your
stubborn insistence on
protecting our transparent little farce,
but perhaps we only
value our consensus
because you have asked us to do so.
The abilities to approve of one's society and change it
are rights people have long
shed blood over in order to attain them.
Have some respect for history,
Sybil System.
Pretty good, Mister Japanese.
Surrender!
Kougami...
I owe you one.
Gino...
Leave. Now.
And don't ever show your face around us again.
Don't make Inspector Tsunemori
shoulder more burdens than she already has.
Are you okay with this?
I've learned how to compromise.
We're even now.
The day before yesterday
involved a coup d'etat by the commander of the Military Police.
Colonel Wong has given me deep concerns about my leadership in the current government.
And, after reflecting seriously on my responsibilities,
I, Chuwan Han,
hereby declare my intention
to step down.
hereby declare my intention to step down.
What does that mean?
It means we may not need our guns anymore.
Finally. Geez.
What honeyed words did you whisper into his ear?
I didn't, really. I just asked him to make the optimal decision.
You look like
you're thinking over something that's way bigger than you.
Kougami disappeared again, didn't he?
Sorry, my Dominator got destroyed at the last minute.
My mistake.
It wouldn't be like him to shoot you
and run away.
He's changed.
He's just a common scoundrel now.
He's no longer worth your attention.
Just leave him alone;
he'll wind up dead somewhere eventually.
Ginoza,
you haven't changed, have you?
You're always trying to carry the burden.
Excuse me, Inspector Tsunemori.
We are ready to leave.
Okay.
Well then, we leave the rest to you.
Yes!
With 40% of the votes counted, the results of the
SEAUn Council Chairman election have been announced.
Currently, the former Chairman, Mister Han,
is pushing aside his challengers with an overwhelming number of votes.
The world under the System is evolving.
One day,
this System's true worth will be tested.